all right
[Music]
yoga is an ancient mind-body discipline
which originated in India thousands of
years ago and that's where most yoga
studies are done to this day this has
raised concerns that national pride
might incline Indian researchers to
quietly shelve any negative results and
just publish studies showing Yoga Works
this fear is not without precedent for
example research conducted in China
Japan Hong Kong and Taiwan was found to
be uniformly favorable to acupuncture
all trials without exception were
positive now one possible explanation
for this findings that acupuncture is
just more effective in countries where
it's traditionally practiced but it is a
little suspicious so are Indian yoga
trials more likely to be positive than
those from other countries they looked
at hundreds of randomized controlled
Trials of yoga both done in India and
done in other countries and trials on
yoga conducted in India had about 25
times times the odds of reaching
positive conclusions as those conducted
elsewhere again yes yoga might be more
effective in India than elsewhere but it
is a little suspicious
so for example if you're interested in
whether yoga is helpful for treating
headaches and you read that yoga appears
to be helpful for those suffering from
tension type headaches but then you find
out nearly all such studies were
conducted in India what do you do with
that information
also notably none of the control groups
any sort of exercise component though
this may be less critical for tension
headaches since neither aerobic exercise
training nor strength training
appears to help them so if we're to
believe the Indian study conclusions
yoga May indeed help with tension
headaches but even they found no effect
for migraines what may help migraines
though is other types of exercise
specifically aerobic exercise decreasing
migraine pain intensity frequency and
duration at least in the short term
what about the benefits of yoga practice
compared to physical exercise and the
management of type 2 diabetes a
significant reduction in both short-term
and longer-term blood sugar control was
noted in the yoga groups compared to
other exercise control groups
however the findings may need to be
interpreted with caution since nearly
half of the studies didn't Define and
adhere to a well-planned exercise
regimen in the control group furthermore
an exercise intervention comparable in
intensity to yoga was followed only in
three out of the eight studies included
and for what it's worth the majority of
the study six out of eight were from
India
when yoga was carefully compared to Sham
yoga which consisted of chair exercises
standing exercises and slow walking to
match the yoga session the relative yoga
benefits evaporated both yoga and Sham
yoga had identical effects on blood
sugar status hence further
well-controlled randomized trials are
required prior to drawing conclusions
about the benefits of yoga in comparison
to physical exercise in patients with
diabetes
similar tentative conclusions were
reached for yoga for osteoarthritis put
all the studies together in yoga May
indeed be effective for improving pain
function and stiffness in individuals
with osteoarthritis of the knee compared
not only to doing nothing but compared
to other kinds of exercise they had some
issues with the quality of some of the
studies and so only a week
recommendation for the use of yoga for
osteoarthritis but hey if you like yoga
or if yoga is the only kind of exercise
you're willing to do then probably
better than nothing
finally in this video let's look at the
effects of yoga compared to active and
inactive controls meaning like compared
to other exercise regiments or just like
doing nothing on physical function and
health related quality of life in adults
aged 60 and older compared to doing
nothing they found clear evidence that
yoga improves physical function and
psychological well-being and older
adults so definitely better than nothing
what about compared to other exercises
yoga pulled ahead for lower limb
strength and lower body flexibility but
for improving balance mobility and
walking speed yoga appeared comparable
psychologically yoga appeared to beat
out other exercises for leaving
depression in older adults but not
anxiety or perceived mental health in
general
[Music]